indexmundi.com 2019-04-08

# IndexMundi Privacy Notice

|   
---|---  
  
* * *

## Scope

This Privacy Policy specifies the handling of your personal information provided by you upon registering on the IndexMundi.com web site. By accepting the Privacy Policy and the User Agreement upon registration, you expressly consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is effective upon acceptance of present Privacy Policy.

## Collection

You can browse IndexMundi.com without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. If you choose to register and you provide us with personal information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers located in the United States. We may collect and store the following personal information:

  1. email address, phone number, physical contact information, and (depending on the service used) sometimes financial information, such as credit card or bank account numbers;
  2. transactional information based on your activities on the site (such as paid membership or purchase of specific IndexMundi products and/or services related to your account);
  3. shipping, billing and other information you provide for selling or buying purposes;
  4. community discussions, chats, dispute resolution, correspondence through our sites, and correspondence sent to us;
  5. other information from your interaction with our site, services, content and advertising, including device ID, computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the sites, ad data, IP address and standard web log information;
  6. additional information we ask you to submit to authenticate yourself or if we believe you are violating site policies (for example, we may ask you to send us an ID or bill to verify your address, or to answer additional questions online to help verify your identity or ownership of an item you list);
  7. information from other companies, such as demographic and navigation data; and
  8. other supplemental information from third parties (for example, if you incur a debt to IndexMundi, we will generally conduct a credit check by obtaining additional information about you from a credit bureau, as permitted by law).

## Marketing

We don't sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their use without your explicit consent. We may combine your information with information we collect from other companies and use it to improve and personalize our services, content and advertising. If you do wish to receive marketing communications from us or to participate in mailing lists you will be asked to opt-in by signing up to receive content related or marketing communication by email from IndexMundi.

## Use

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. You agree that we may use your personal information to:

  1. provide the services and customer support you request;
  2. troubleshoot problems;
  3. prevent, detect, and investigate potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our User Agreement;
  4. customize, measure and improve our services, content and advertising;
  5. tell you about our services, content or service updates, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences; and
  6. compare information for accuracy, and verify it with third parties;
  7. and other uses as described when we collect the information.

## Our Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a listing or other content violates the rights of others, or protect anyone's rights, property, or safety. Such information will be disclosed in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

We may also share your personal information with:

  1. Other IndexMundi websites to provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and violations of our policies.
  2. Law enforcement, governmental agencies, or authorized third-parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other IndexMundi user to legal liability. In such events, we will disclose information relevant to the investigation, such as name, city, state, ZIP code, telephone number, email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, bidding and listing history, and anything else we may deem relevant to the investigation.
  3. Other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. (Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information will be used contrary to this policy, you will receive prior notice.)

Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect your privacy and our ability to keep the community free from bad user, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement, other government officials, or other third parties without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity.

## Information You Share on IndexMundi

Your User ID is displayed throughout the IndexMundi site (and so available to the public), and is connected to all of your IndexMundi activity. Other people can see your product listings and details, and request for quotes. Notices sent to other community members about suspicious activity and policy violations on our sites refer to User IDs and specific items. So if you associate your name with your User ID, the people to whom you have revealed your name will be able to personally identify your IndexMundi activities.

If you access our sites from a shared computer or a computer in an internet café, certain information about you, such as your User ID and website activity on IndexMundi, may also be visible to other individuals who use the computer after you.

## Using Information from IndexMundi

IndexMundi enables you to share personal and business information with other users. We encourage you to disclose your privacy practices and respect the privacy of other users. We cannot guarantee the privacy or security of your information and therefore we encourage you to evaluate the privacy and security policies of your trading partner before entering into a transaction and choosing to share your information. To help protect your privacy, we allow only limited access to other users' contact, shipping and financial information to facilitate your potential transactions. When users are involved in a transaction, they may have access to each other's name, User ID, email address and other contact and shipping information. In all cases, you must give other users a chance to remove themselves from your database and a chance to review what information you have collected about them.

You agree to use user information only for:

  * transaction-related purposes that are not unsolicited commercial messages;
  * using services offered through IndexMundi (such as product listings and request for quotes), or
  * other purposes that a user expressly chooses.

## Cookies

We use "cookies" (small files placed on your hard drive) on certain of our pages to help analyze our web page flow; customize our services, content and advertising; measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety.

A few important things you should know about cookies are that:

  1. We offer certain features that are available only through the use of cookies.
  2. We use cookies to help identify you and maintain your signed-in status.
  3. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session.
  4. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of some of our sites or services.

## No Spam, Spyware or Spoofing

IndexMundi and its users do not tolerate spam. You are not licensed to add other IndexMundi users’ contact information to your database with the purpose of sending unsolicited business or marketing materials, even if a user has participated in a business transaction with you, without their express consent. In the same manner you are not allowed to use such information to send spam, or spyware to such users’ email accounts. To report spam or spoof emails to IndexMundi, please forward the email to webmaster@indexmundi.com. You may not use our communication tools to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate IndexMundi’s User Agreement. We automatically scan and may manually filter messages to check for spam, viruses, phishing attacks and other malicious activity or illegal or prohibited content, but we do not permanently store messages sent through these tools. If you send an email to an email address that is not registered in our community (via Refer-a-Friend or other tools), we do not permanently store that email or use that email address for any marketing purpose. We do not rent or sell these email addresses.

## Account Protection

Your password is the key to your account. Use unique numbers, letters and special characters, and do not disclose your IndexMundi password to anyone. If you do share your password or your personal information with others, remember that you are responsible for all actions taken in the name of your account. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately notify IndexMundi and change your password.

## Accessing, Reviewing and Changing Your Personal Information

You can see, review and change most of your personal information by signing on to IndexMundi. Generally, we will not manually modify your personal information because it is very difficult to verify your identity remotely. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. Once you make a public posting, you may not be able to change or remove it. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law. We do retain personal information from closed accounts to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our User Agreement, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

## Security

Your information is stored on our servers located in the United States. We treat data as an asset that must be protected and use lots of tools (encryption, passwords, physical security, etc.) to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure. However, as you probably know, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the site. Therefore, although we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

## Third Parties

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. If you disclose your information to others, whether they are buyers or sellers on the IndexMundi website or other sites throughout the internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. IndexMundi does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.

## General

We the reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the amended terms on this site. All amended terms take effect immediately after they are posted on the site. In addition, we will notify you by email if such amendment takes place.
